以前在那些即将死去的人身上......
Previously on
Those About to Die...
并非所有的犹太人都对他们的女王的想法感到满意
Not all the Judeans are comfortable
with the idea of their queen
为你哥哥张开双腿。
spreading her legs
for your brother.
我相信你的兄弟图密善要为粮食延误负责。
I believe your brother Domitian
is responsible for the grain delays.
还有食物骚乱。
And the food riots.
- 你有证据吗？- 其中一艘运粮船上的领航员
- Do you have proof?
- A navigator on one of the grain ships
在我们说话的时候，正在被护送到这里。
is being escorted
here as we speak.
这一刻即将到来。
The moment is upon us.
我们杀了我的兄弟。
We kill my brother.
我们可以在禁卫军中买到谁？
Who among the
Praetorians can we buy?
一千万塞斯特斯的黄金，两天后，在这个地方。
Ten million sesterces in gold, two
days from now, here in this place.
天蝎座，我会在赛道上面对他，
Scorpus, I will face
him on the track,
我要打败他。
and I will defeat him.
我们需要说话。
We need to speak.
离开我们。
Leave us.
马尼利乌斯要求 1000 万塞斯特斯。
Manilius demands
10 million sesterces.
是的。等我当了皇帝，我可以付钱给他。
Yes. After I'm emperor,
I can pay him that.
不然我就杀了他。
Or I'll kill him.
他现在想要它，提前。
He wants it now, in advance.
这不可能。
It's impossible.
没有我们的奖金，就没有办法。
Without our winnings,
there is no way.
更糟糕的是，莱托会见了提图斯
What's worse,
Leto met with Titus
并以惊人的准确性列出了我所做的事情。
and laid out, with surprising
accuracy, what I had done.
- 提图斯知道吗？- 是的，也不是。
- Titus knows?
- Yes and no.
他不知道该相信谁，是我还是莱托。
He doesn't know who
to believe, me or Leto.
-京？- 也许有办法。
- Ten million?
- Perhaps there is a way.
一个赌注。
A bet.
今天，我们把我们所拥有的一切都押在一轮赌注上。
We wager everything we
have on a round bet, today.
天蝎座在第七圈取得领先。
Scorpus to take the
lead on the seventh lap.
- 我会确保它发生。- 我们不要抓住稻草。
- I'll make sure it happens.
- Let's not grasp at straws.
这就是我们所拥有的。
That's all we have.
如果我们赢了，我们将有足够的钱支付马尼利乌斯
If we win, we'll have
enough to pay Manilius
以及我们需要的尽可能多的禁卫军。
and as many of the
Praetorian Guards as we need.
是的。让我们开始吧。
Yes, yes. Let's do it.
哥哥
Brother,
你看起来很激动。
you seem agitated.
不，只是深思熟虑。
No, just thoughtful.
尽管我对这一切感到兴奋，
As much as I
thrill at all of this,
两天后，我们将开放圆形剧场，
in two days we open
our amphitheater,
这个地方失去了一些神奇的东西。
and this place loses
something that's magic.
这是真的。
That's true enough.
但正如你所指出的，它也放松了束缚
But as you pointed out, it
also loosens the stranglehold
贵族控制着我们的城市。
the Patricians
have over our city.
- 说得好。- 这是你的话。
- Well put.
- It's your words.
我知道。
I know.
埃利亚。让我们来谈谈这个问题。
Elia. Let's talk this through.
我们正在做一个非常大的回合赌注。
We're making a
very large round bet.
把它摊开到其他板上，
Spread it out to
the other boards,
但要保持安静，这样我们就不会放弃我们的赔率。
but keep it quiet so
we don't drop our odds.
你说“我们”？这是否意味着我分一杯羹？
You said "we"? Does that
mean I have a piece of it?
做到这一点，你会得到十分之一。
Make this happen,
and you get a tenth.
天蝎座将在第七场比赛中领先。
Scorpus will take the
lead in the seventh.
我需要去确保这将会发生，
I need to go and make
sure that's what will happen,
并得到最后的珠宝和契约。
and get the last of the
jewelry and the deeds.
把所有赌注都押在一场比赛上是有风险的。
Betting everything
on one race is risky.
别无选择。
No other choice.
生死攸关。
Life or death.
要么全有，要么全无。
All or nothing.
它是天蝎座。
It is Scorpus.
我需要你做点什么。
I need something from you.
每个人都想从天蝎座那里得到一些东西。
Everyone wants
something from Scorpus.
我今天把我所拥有的一切都放在你身上。
I'm putting everything
I have on you today.
-万事。-哼。
- Everything.
- Huh.
当然，天蝎座会赢，但是......
Of course, Scorpus
will win, but...
这是意料之中的。机会不会那么好。
That's expected. The
odds won't be so good.
徒劳无功。
Vain fuck.
你去哪了？
Where have you been?
你获胜的几率不像以前那么好了。
The odds on you winning
aren't as good as they used to be.
- 我们下注的是一轮。 - 一轮修复？
- We're on a round bet.
- A round fix?
这么接近比赛？不。
This close to the race? No.
不，这是不可能的。
No, it's impossible.
设置太难了。要带进来的司机太多了，才能让它看起来很真实。
It's too hard to set up. Too many
drivers to bring in to make it look real.
我不在乎！
I don't care!
我需要你在第七天带头。
I need you to take the
lead on the seventh.
握住它并获胜。
Hold it and win.
我的作品是什么？
What's my piece?
你的生活。
Your life.
没有这个，图密善就死了，我们也死了。
Without this, Domitian's
dead, and so are we.
明白了？
Got it?
去其他博彩酒馆下注。
Go to the other betting
taverns and bet it all.
黄金，我的财产契约，一切。
Gold, the deeds to my
properties, everything.
你把小屁孩藏在哪里？
Where do you hide the chits?
-是否确定？-抓住他们。
- Are you sure?
- Get them.
在努米底亚，豹子将猎物拖到树上。
In Numidia, leopards
drag their prey up into trees.
较高的地方更适合隐藏有价值的东西。
Higher places are better
for hiding things of value.
去。
Go.
我需要帮助。
I need help.
鲁弗斯，过来。
Rufus, come here.
拿着这些，跟从我。
Take these, and follow me.
较高的地方更适合隐藏有价值的东西。
Higher places are better
for hiding things of value.
- 氙气死了。- 是的，这样的悲剧。
- Xenon died.
- Yes, such a tragedy.
所以我想，“为什么不选择黄金呢？
So I thought, "Why
not go with Gold?"
好决定。
Good decision.
奥托，在那边。
Otho, over there.
方索亚在第一场比赛中？
Fonsoa is in the first race?
是的，他是。
Yes, he is.
现在你明白了吗，小兄弟？这个的吸引力。
Now do you see, little
brother? The appeal of this.
加油。
Come on.
你一定感觉到是什么吸引了安德里亚和我。
You must feel what
lured Andria and I to this.,
罗马市民，
Citizens of Rome,
我向你们介绍今天的第一场比赛！
I present to you the
first race of today!
后座！准备！
Pillions! Ready!
嗨！
Hiya!
嘿，奥托，你想吃点东西吗？你饿了吗？
Hey, Otho, would you like
some food? Are you hungry?
快点！跑！
Move it! Run!
开门。埃利亚，拜托了。请打开。
Open up. Elia, please.
Please open up.
搬过来。
Move over.
不！方索阿！
No! Fonsoa!
方索阿！
Fonsoa!
奥托，过来。
Otho, come.
去看医生。快 点。
Get the physician. Hurry.
腿。
The legs.
不要放弃。请。
Don't give up. Please.
一切都会好起来的。
It'll be all right.
请和我在一起，拜托。
Please stay with me, please.
埃利亚。
Elia.
你还记得我摔断腿的时候吗？
Do you remember
when I broke my leg?
答案是肯定的。傻事。
Of course. Foolish thing.
你把我带回家。
You carried me home.
爷爷，他走了。
Grandfather, he was gone.
你抱着我，而安德里亚把我的腿放在一边。
You held me while
Andria set my leg.
当我哭泣时，你整夜抱着我。
You held me all
night long while I cried.
它一定很痛。
It must have hurt.
不是这样的。
Not like this.
对不起。
I'm sorry.
不！
No!
不。
No.
嘿。天蝎座死了。
Hey. Scorpus is dead.
天蝎座死了！
Scorpus is dead!
我下令将斯科普斯关押在这里。
I ordered Scorpus' internment
to be here at the spint.
我本来会为他委托建造一座宏伟的雕像，但是......
I would have commissioned
a grand statue for him, but...
在我看到它之前，我就已经死了。
I'll be dead
before I can see it.
他是我的朋友。
He was my friend.
我会委托雕像。
I'll commission the statue.
你也会死的。
You'll be dead, too.
我们打赌，我们输了。
We bet, and we lost.
现在，很快我们就死了。
Now, soon we die.
也许不会那么快。
Perhaps not so soon.
我们打赌，我们输了，
We bet, we lost,
但我找到了我们的奖金。
but I found our winnings.
覆盖马尼利乌斯绰绰有余。
And it's more than
enough to cover Manilius.
什么？
What?
如何？
How?
这有关系吗？
Does it matter?
不。
No.
现在我们也有天蝎座的份额。
And now we have
Scorpus' share as well.
我想我们会的。
I suppose we do.
从这里可以欣赏到更好的景色。
A much better view from here.
谁会想到几步就能产生如此大的差异？
Who would have thought a couple of
paces would make such a difference?
站在这里的壮丽景色是您的合作伙伴，而不仅仅是客户。
A grand view standing here as
your partner and not just a client.
我的，我的。
My, my.
我们雄心勃勃，不是吗？
We are ambitious, aren't we?
是的，我们是。
Yes, we are.
而你，甚至不是贵族。
And you, not even a Patrician.
不要太确定。
Don't be so sure about that.
如果是这样，我最好有你做我的仆人。
If so, all the better for me
to have you as my servant.
对不起。
Excuse me.
我有一个再见要处理。
I have a goodbye to attend to.
大家都出去。
Everybody out.
可惜你现在会错过所有的乐趣。
Shame you'll miss
all the fun now.
没有你，就不会有那么多的笑声。
There won't be as much
of a laugh without you.
飞驰穿过冥河，享受极乐世界的美酒之旅......
Speed across the River Styx to the
wine-soaked pleasures of Elysium...
你这个了不起的醉汉混蛋。
you wonderful, drunken bastard.
如果不是我的愤怒，就没有坟墓可以挖了。
Were it not for my rage,
there would be no grave to dig.
归咎于命运。
Blame the Fates.
不是你自己。
Not yourself.
萨琳娜，我必须来。
Salena, I had to come.
多么可怕的悲剧。
What a terrible tragedy.
请允许我弥补。
Please, allow me to make amends.
睡吧。
Go to sleep.
我为我的触摸道歉。
I apologize for my touch.
你能让我重新开始吗？
Will you let me begin again?
说出你必须说的话，然后离开。
Say what you must, then leave.
没有义务，我要求你与我的辩护人会面。
Without obligation, I ask that
you meet with my advocate.
他相信你有充分的理由拿回你在蓝派的股份。
He believes you have a strong case to
get back your shares in the Blue Faction.
继续。
Go on.
我相信你已经生了三个孩子。
You have had three
children, I believe.
只有奥托活着。
Only Otho lives.
另外两个还很年轻，当他们......
The other two are
very young, when they...
然后适用 jus trium liberorum。
Then the jus trium
liberorum applies.
当一个女人生了三个孩子时，她是自由的
When a woman has had
three children, she is free
来自她丈夫的监护权。
from the guardianship
of her husband.
-意义？- 你的就是你的。
- Meaning?
- What is yours is yours.
那些股份是你的，不是你丈夫的。
Those shares were
yours, not your husband's.
他从你那里偷走了它们，
He stole them from you,
因此，将它们出售给马苏斯领事是无效的。
and so the sale of them to
Consul Marsus was invalid.
这是无法证明的。
This can't be proven.
它已经得到证明。
It is already proven.
它只需要在法庭上争论。
It needs only to
be argued in court.
这是一个昂贵但可行的过程。
An expensive, but
doable process.
我们多久可以与您的倡导者会面？
How soon can we meet
with your advocate?
一个傻瓜的赌注，你输了。
A fool's bet, and you lost.
我失去了一个，
I lost one,
并赢得了另一个。
and won another.
我们埋葬死者，勇往直前。
We bury the dead
and forge ahead.
为我写这些。
Write these for me.
两个卷轴将是相同的。
Both scrolls will be the same.
我可以相信你吗？
Can I trust you?
是的，也不是。
Yes and no.
这与你的孩子无关。
This has nothing to
do with your children.
好。现在写。
Good. Now write.
- 数一数。- 都排序好了？
- Count it.
- All sorted?
提多将在睡梦中死去。
Titus will die in his sleep.
- 波尔图呢？- 他很快就会死去。
- And Porto?
- He will die shortly after.
以及那些忠于他的禁卫军。
Along with those
Praetorians loyal to him.
我在奥斯蒂亚有人监视导航员的到来。
I have people in Ostia monitoring
the arrival of the navigator.
无论你做什么，都要快点。
Whatever you do, do it fast.
作为交易的一部分，
As part of the deal,
我已经写了双重忏悔。
I've written out
dual confessions.
如果我们中的任何一个背叛了另一个，我们都会死。
If either of us betray
the other, we both die.
还有图密善和我们在一起。
And Domitian with us.
两张简单的羊皮纸，任何一张都足以让我们被杀，
Two simple parchments, either
one enough to see us killed,
任何一个都足以让我们活着。
either one enough
to keep us alive.
取决于谁持有它们。
Depending on who holds them.
大功告成。
It's done.
而现在，只要你活着，
And now, for as
long as you live,
你的头上悬着一把剑。
you have a sword
dangling over your head.
- 就像那个传说中的希腊人一样。-达摩克利斯？
- Like that legendary Greek.
- Damocles?
跟我来。
Follow me.
我们都生活在一把悬在头上的剑上，卡拉。
We all live with a sword
dangling over our heads, Cala.
只是我知道。
It's just that I know it.
推到这里。
Push here.
你疯了。
You're mad.
你现在也身处其中。
You're in this, too, now.
然后我们俩都疯了。
Then we are both mad.
拜托，我求求你了。
Please, I beg you.
我有重要的信息要告诉皇帝。
I have important
information for the emperor.
他会付给你比你想象的更多的钱
He will pay you more
than you can imagine
当他听到我要说的话时。
when he hears
what I have to say.
你到底想告诉我哥哥什么？
And what precisely do
you want to tell my brother?
求求你了，我的爱人。
Please, I beg you, my love.
那你为什么不求我呢？
Then why don't you beg for me?
在众神的见证下，
By all the gods,
我后悔我做了什么，我再也不会这样做了。
I regret what I've done, and
I will never, ever do it again.
我永远不会谈论它。
I will never speak of it.
不。
No.
你不会。
You won't.
你已经知道太多了。
You already know too much.
我不能让你把秘密泄露给我哥哥。
I can't have you spilling
secrets to my brother.
不，请不要。不要！
No, please, don't. Don't!
-停。-下。
- Stop.
- Down.
这是个坏消息。
It's bad news.
图密善正在收购禁卫军。
Domitian is buying
Praetorian Guards.
他是黄金派系的部分所有者。
He's part owner
of the Gold Faction.
这就是他得到所有钱的地方。
That's where he's
getting all his money.
告诉我你有证据。
Tell me you have proof.
- 只有我听到的。- 那么谁能确定呢？
- Only what I've heard.
- Then who would know for certain?
卡拉经营着他的书。
Cala runs his books.
我相信她最小的女儿在马苏斯领事的家里当奴隶。
I believe her youngest daughter is in
the home of the Consul Marsus as a slave.
是的。
Yeah.
向上。
Up.
我是来看你的情妇的。
I'm here to see your mistress.
殿下。
Your Highness.
我们有同样的敌人，安东尼娅。
We have the same enemy, Antonia.
那会是谁呢？
And who might that be?
你非常清楚它是谁。
You know perfectly
well who it is.
你被马尔苏斯领事的妻子安东尼娅·科内利亚召见。
You are summoned by Antonia
Cornelia, wife of the Consul Marsus.
我？
Me?
为什么？
For what?
安东尼娅夫人想和你说话
The Lady Antonia
wishes to speak to you
关于你的女儿朱拉，她是她家的奴隶。
about your daughter Jula,
who's a slave in her house.
记住，不要太快。
Remember, not too quick.
在你把它交给他们之前，让人群等待它。
Let the crowd wait for it
before you give it to them.
我想你可能终于找到了自己的使命。
I think you may have
finally found your calling.
血腥运动，表演者，
Blood sports, showman,
它适合你。
it suits you.
我在远处的座位上坐了足够长的时间
I spent long enough
sitting in the far seats
知道暴徒想要什么。
to know what the mob wants.
我的女士们。
My ladies.
你想和我谈谈我的女儿吗？
You wish to speak to
me about my daughter?
我有机会买到她的自由吗？
Is there a chance I
might buy her freedom?
你误会了。
You misunderstand.
-妈妈！放手！不！- 离开她。离开她。
- Mother! Let go! No!
- Leave her. Leave her.
安静。
Quiet.
你的女儿一直在监视我和我丈夫。
Your daughter has been
spying on my husband and me.
这种罪行应判处死刑。
Such an offense warrants death.
我有权利和权力这样做
And I am within my
rights and power to do it
以我选择的任何方式。
in any manner I choose.
你为一个男人工作，Tenax。
You work for a man, Tenax.
你住在他的家里。
You reside in his home.
这个人是弗拉维乌斯·多米提亚努斯的客户，
This man is a client
of Flavius Domitianus,
皇帝的兄弟。
the brother of the emperor.
我猜你的女儿是在向他报告，
I presume your daughter
was reporting to him,
通过你。
through you.
图密善和特纳克斯负责逮捕我的丈夫马苏斯领事。
Domitian and Tenax are responsible for
the arrest of my husband, Consul Marsus.
你知道他们正在策划政变吗
Did you know they
were planning a coup
反对提图斯皇帝？
against the Emperor Titus?
我就是这么想的。
That's what I thought.
我们需要证明他们有计划的背叛。
We need proof of
their planned betrayal.
只有这样，你才能拯救你的女儿。
Only with that will you
save your daughter.
她的沉默很能说明问题。
Her silence speaks volumes.
如果有这样的证据，
If there is such proof,
我怎么知道你会信守诺言
how do I know you
will keep your word
不会伤害我的女儿吗？
and will not harm my daughter?
300多年来，我的家族一直为罗马提供执政官。
My family has been furnishing
Rome with consuls for over 300 years.
我在撒谎之上。
I am above lying.
但我理解你缺乏信任。
But I understand
your lack of trust.
不，不，不，不，不要，不要，拜托。
No, no, no, no,
don't, don't, please.
我可以给你证明。
I can get you your proof.
但不要伤害她。
But don't hurt her.
现在由你决定。
It is up to you now.
你要到中午。
You have until midday.
否则，你的女儿就会死。
If not, your daughter will die.
现在，走吧。
Now, go.
听
Listen,
地球上最伟大的城市的人们，
people of the
greatest city on Earth,
让游戏开始吧！
let the games begin!
振作起来，兄弟。
Brace yourself, brother.
你即将赢得整个罗马的崇拜。
You're about to win the
adoration of all of Rome.
我总是这样想象。
I always imagined it like this.
离得这么近，你可以看到
So close you can see
万事。
everything.
- 准备好鸟儿。- 准备好鸟儿。
- Ready the birds.
- 准备好鸟儿。- 鸟儿。
- The birds.
- 释放它们。- 释放它们。
- Release them.
释放它们。
Release them.
你已经超越了自己，兄弟。
You've outdone
yourself, brother.
这是一件很特别的事情。
This is something special.
光环。
Aura.
光环，这是什么？
Aura, what is this?
- 这怎么可能？-请原谅我。
- How can this be?
- Please forgive me.
- 原谅你什么？- 为了一切。
- Forgive you for what?
- For everything.
我是你来到这个舞台的原因，
I am the reason you
are here in this arena,
朱拉是奴隶，我们的母亲在罗马。
that Jula is a slave, that
our mother is in Rome.
我是一切的根源。
I am the cause of everything.
- 你在保护朱拉。- 看看我们从哪里来的。
- You were protecting Jula.
- And look at where that got us.
我已经把自己卖给了卢杜斯。
I have sold myself to the Ludus.
你认为你的死会让我们更容易吗？
Do you think your death
will make it easier for us?
也许不适合你，
Perhaps not for you,
但对我来说。
but for me.
夸。
Kwame.
-来。-光环。
- Come.
- Aura.
-关门。- 你姐姐？
- Close the door.
- Your sister?
- 并拉。-拉。
- And pull.
- Pull.
拉！
Pull!
妮卡，我的女孩，仔细听。
Nica, my girl, listen carefully.
参议员。
Senators.
特纳克斯，解放我们。您将获得超出梦想的利润。
Tenax, free us. You'll
profit beyond your dreams.
领事。
Consul.
这太疯狂了。你知道他也会杀了你。
This is madness. You
know he'll kill you, too.
我们都会死！
We will all die!
闭嘴！
Shut up!
特纳克斯。
Tenax.
打开大门。
Open the gates.
你不能这么做。
You can't do this.
请！
Please!
特纳克斯！
Tenax!
看看那些贵族的婊子。
Look at those Patrician
sons of bitches.
现在离 Aventine 还有很长的路要走吗？
A long way from
the Aventine now?
认识埃及鳄鱼神索贝克
Meet Sobek, the
Egyptian crocodile god
来自尼罗河的黑暗水域。
from the dark
waters of the Nile.
后世的恶魔。
The demon of the hereafter.
留在这里。等等我。
Stay here. Wait for me.
- 你带了吗？- 得到我的女儿。
- Have you brought it?
- Get my daughter.
把她交给我，然后你就会得到你的证据。
Hand her over to me,
then you'll get your proof.
去找她。
Go get her.
-妈妈。-安静。
- Mother.
- Quiet.
尼卡。
Nica.
证明。
Proof.
向上。向上。
Up. Up.
你是自由的。
You're free.
停。
Stop.
这是朱拉，执政官马苏斯家的女奴吗？
Is this Jula, slave girl of the
House of the Consul Marsus,
角斗士夸梅的妹妹？
sister of the gladiator Kwame?
这是关于什么的？
What's this about?
- 带走她。她现在是罗马的财产。-不。不，不，停下来。
- Take her. She is now the property of Rome.
- No. No, no, stop.
请。这是关于什么的？
Please. What is this about?
妈妈！妈妈！-你要带她去哪里？请！
Mother! Mother!
-Where are you taking her? Please!
加油！
Come on!
-现在。-现在！
- Now.
- Now!
现在！
Now!
当塞特谋杀他的兄弟奥西里斯时，
When Seth murdered
his brother Osiris,
伊希斯派出强大的索贝克向塞特复仇。
Isis sent out the mighty Sobek
to take vengeance on Seth.
索贝克会怜悯叛徒吗？
Will Sobek show
mercy on the traitors?
或。。。
Or...
他们会报仇吗？
Will they take revenge?
我们确定吗？
Are we sure about this?
毕竟，他是执政官，他们是参议员。
After all, he is a consul,
and they are senators.
更有理由公开奖励他们的背叛。
All the more reason to
reward their betrayal publicly.
我想你是对的。
I suppose you're right.
特纳克斯，你的手下之一，一直在监视奥斯蒂亚港
Tenax, one of your men who's
been watching Ostia Harbor
告诉我，风平浪静带来了某位领航员
tells me that fair winds have
brought a certain navigator
比预期更早到达奥斯蒂亚。
to Ostia earlier than expected.
他将于今天下午抵达。
He is to arrive this afternoon.
加油！
Come on!
小心！
Look out!
那不是你的孩子吗？
Wasn't that your boy?
兄弟，你对娱乐的品味从未停止过让我感到震惊。
Your taste in entertainment
never ceases to appall me, brother.
让开。为安东尼娅夫人让路。
Make way. Make way
for the Lady Antonia.
你，停下来。不允许女性入内。
You, stop. No women allowed.
上层甲板的 22 号登机口。
Gate 22 for the upper deck.
我是安东尼娅·文明，马苏斯领事的妻子。让开。
I'm Antonia Civilius, the wife of
the Consul Marsus. Step aside.
- 你退到一边。- 不要碰我！
- You step aside.
- Do not touch me!
出去。
Get out.
现在。
Now.
继续。你也是。
Go on. You, too.
我是贝伦妮丝，犹太人的王后，提图斯皇帝的配偶。
I am Berenice, queen of the Judeans
and consort of the Emperor Titus.
我要求和他谈谈。
I demand to speak to him.
今天是什么？
What is it today?
- 我是女王... - 她在那里。
- I am queen...
- There she is.
我们不会再有机会杀死这个妓女了。
We won't get another
chance to kill this whore.
现在，不要失去她。
Now, don't lose her.
我有一件最重要的事情要送给提图斯皇帝。
I have something of the utmost
importance to give to the Emperor Titus.
我要求和他说话！
I demand to speak to him!
- 压低声音。- 现在放开我，
- Keep your voice down.
- Let go of me now,
不然我就把你禀报给皇帝。
or I'll report you
to the emperor.
他会听到这个。
He will hear of this.
你会因为给他而得到奖励，如果你不这样做，你会受到惩罚。
You will be rewarded for giving it
to him or be punished if you don't.
你不明白吗？
Don't you understand?
对，给我就行了。
Right, just give it to me.
把你所拥有的给我，我会亲自带给他。
Give me what you have
and I'll take it to him myself.
不。从我的手到他的手。
No. From my hand to his.
要么就是这样，要么什么都没有。
It's either that, or nothing.
好吧，那就没什么了。
Well, then it's nothing.
你会为你的傲慢而死。
And you will die
for your insolence.
- 罗马低能儿！- 野蛮妓女！
- Roman imbeciles!
- Barbarian whore!
女性的上层甲板在哪里？
Where's the upper
deck for women?
给他拿点东西喝。
Fetch him something to drink.
我需要和图密善殿下谈谈，这很紧急。
I need to speak with His
Highness Domitian, it's urgent.
回来。
Get back.
返回。
Back.
Tenax 需要和你说话。
Tenax needs to speak to you.
等一下，兄弟。
A moment, brother.
是的，很好。
Yes, very well.
我们没时间了。
We're out of time.
领航员今天下午抵达奥斯蒂亚。
The navigator arrives
in Ostia this afternoon.
所以，一切都结束了。
So, it's over.
提多赢了，我们死了。
Titus wins and we die.
不。
No.
如果我们推进我们的计划，就不会。
Not if we move
our plans forward.
此时此地杀了他。
Kill him here and now.
什么？你疯了吗？
What? Are you mad?
- 我们有什么选择？- 你不能杀他
- What choice do we have?
- You cannot kill him
在整个罗马面前。
in front of all of Rome.
把提图斯从椅子上弄起来，走到前厅。
Get Titus out of his chair
and up into the anteroom.
剩下的就交给我吧。
I'll do the rest.
他的警卫呢？
What about his guards?
一旦他死了，他们就会看着你。
Once he's dead,
they will look to you.
他们的新皇帝。
Their new emperor.
尽快负责，阻止他们杀我。
Take charge as quickly as you
can to stop them from killing me.
如果情况很糟糕，我对此一无所知。
If this goes badly,
I knew nothing of it.
答案是肯定的。去。
Of course. Go.
我们需要说话。
We need to speak.
独自。
Alone.
很好。
Very well.
皇帝。
Emperor.
波尔图。我和我哥哥，我们只是......
Porto. Me and my
brother, we were just...
这是最重要的。
It is of the utmost importance.
很好。
Very well.
等一下，兄弟。
One moment, brother.
谷物船队导航员在奥斯蒂亚。
The grain fleet
navigator is in Ostia.
他有一艘船的日志证明。
He has a ship's log proof.
证明你哥哥耽误了粮食发货。
Proof that your brother
delayed the grain shipments.
把他带到我这里来。
Bring him to me.
我认为我们自己去奥斯蒂亚更安全。
I think it's safer that we
go to Ostia ourselves.
难道你不相信你的手下会把他带到这里来吗？
Do you not trust your
men to bring him here?
我现在不相信任何人。
I don't trust anyone
at the moment.
所以事情就到了这个地步。准备护送。
So it's come to that.
Prepare an escort.
皇帝和我自己的新鲜马匹。
Fresh horses for the
emperor and myself.
全套贴身警卫已安装并准备就绪。
Full personal guard
mounted and ready.
在这件事得到解决之前，我不会离开你的身边。
I'm not leaving your
side until this is settled.
我能信任的人太少了。
There's so few I can trust.
我很感激你，波尔图。
I'm grateful for you, Porto.
我的主，我会保护你。
I shall guard you, my lord.
去。
Go.
哥哥，你是说？
Brother, you were saying?
我只是担心你的安全，
I was only worried
for your safety,
哥哥。
brother.
为那些与马苏斯领事结盟的人报仇。
Revenge, for those
aligned with Consul Marsus.
但现在你的指挥官在这里，
But now your commander is here,
我相信你会安全的。
I'm sure you'll be safe.
是的。
Yes.
提多！提多！
Titus! Titus!